FRONT END DEVELOPER
SARA KEVORKIAN
sdkevorkian@gmail.com
253-332-7341
Seattle, WA

SUMMARY
I am a Seattle-based front end developer that has delivered for a variety of industries including non-profit, real estate, big oil, and airlines. I am primarily a front end
developer with some back end development experience. My background in biotech taught me the importance of flexibility and the mindset to break concepts down into
testable pieces. I am an analytical thinker and love to ask questions, while keeping a collaborative, positive mindset. In my 3+ years of experience I have learned new
technologies quickly to meet project needs.
EXPERIENCE
Sr Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle AVANADE, Dec. 2019 - Current
Ownership of front end features while creating responsive, engaging web experiences
Build reusable, easily maintainable components or design patterns with accessibility best practices
Provide guidance on technical feasibility for new designs
Work closely with design and client teams to clarify requirements
Collaborate with backend developers on data structures and transfer
Research approaches to challenging features and create proofs of concept
Present project work or new technologies at internal meetings
Mentor two junior front end developers in their careers
Notable Projects:
April 2020 - Current
Using React/Redux, delivered a public-facing nonprofit site to connect donors and volunteers during COVID-19 in 1 month
Extended into enhancement/maintenance phase
Implemented social media tracking pixels, Google Tag Manager, and Google Analytics
July 2019 - April 2020
Delivered a new internal employee Sharepoint productivity hub for a large corporation
Lead FED within a primarily offshore team
Launched pilot stage in 3 months and was extended into second phase of project
While on this project received Avanade North America's November "Recognizing Excellence" award and Seattle team's "Studio Champ" for January 2020
Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle Dec. 2018 - Current
Notable Projects:
May 2019 - June 2019
Built the UI of a workflow app for developers to bring new apps to the cloud using React
Lead FED on a team with two junior onshore FEDs
June 2018 - Feb 2019
Delivered a simpler and more intuitive version of a US airline’s internal policy search tool using Sitecore and Coveo
Lead FED on a team with one junior onshore FED
Sr Analyst - Front End Developer, Seattle Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018
Notable Projects:
April 2018 - June 2018
As the Lead FED, integrated the newest version of Coveo search into an existing Angular/Sitecore intranet site
Guided a junior developer to finish remaining bugs within a set bucket of hours
While on this project awarded Seattle team's "Studio Champ" for May 2018
Aug 2017 - March 2018
Worked with the existing development team to solve UI bugs for a Coveo-driven Sitecore corporate real estate search site
Extended as the sole front end developer - responsible for performance enhancement and new feature requests
Improved performance of business critical property search page by 50-75%
Web Development Immersive, Seattle GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Mar. 2017 - June 2017
Accelerated project oriented learning - 50+ hours per week over 3 months. Worked individually and as a team to develop full-stack web applications.
Clinical Research Associate - Molecular Analysis / QC Lead, Seattle HEMATOLOGICS INC., Nov. 2014 - Feb. 2017
Worked within an interdisciplinary team performing clinical DNA testing; prepared molecular lab for CAP audit
Molecular Technologist II/Quality Assistant, Seattle GENELEX CORPORATION, Sept. 2013 - Nov. 2014
Performed high throughput clinical DNA testing; managed purchasing and quality databases.
Molecular Technologist I, Seattle Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013
Molecular Technician, Seattle Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2012
EDUCATION
GENERAL ASSEMBLY
Web Development Immersive 2017
WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY
B. S. Cellular and Molecular Biology/Biochemistry 2011
SKILLS
TOOLS HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React, Angular.js,
Bootstrap, SQL, MongoDB, Web APIs, Git/Github, Materialize, Coveo,
Sitecore, SASS, LESS, Gulp, Grunt, Akumina, Sharepoint
ABILITIES Troubleshooting, Teamwork, Communication, Flexibility, Positivity,
Organization, Self-Reliance